Mama.
媽媽
Yanyan.
巖巖
Mama. Yanyan.
媽媽，巖巖
Hiro. Say bye to Papa.
小宏，跟爸爸說再見
Mama.
媽媽
-Mitsuki. -Yes?
美月
You don't have to stay up and wait for me.
晚上不用等我
I mean it.
真的
Mama.
媽媽
-Okay. -Yanyan.
-好 -巖巖
Mama.
媽媽
Bye.
我出門了
-Have a good day. -Mama.
-上班愉快 -媽媽
Yanyan.
巖巖
Mama.
媽媽
Okay, let's watch Yanyan.
好，我們去看巖巖
-Yanyan. -Yeah.
巖巖
Let's Yanyan together.
來和巖巖一起玩吧
LET'S YANYAN TOGETHER
（和巖巖一起玩）
Yanyan.
巖巖
BASED ON THE MANGA "1122" BY PEKO WATANABE
（根據渡邊平子同名漫畫改編）
1122: FOR A HAPPY MARRIAGE
電視劇名：1122 好夫妻
Ichiko,
一子
you finally had your first brothel experience.
妳終於有了風俗館初體驗
Congratulations.
恭喜
Is it something to congratulate?
這種事也要恭喜嗎？
So, how was it?
怎麼樣？
Well…
這個嘛…
Absolutely
簡直
mind blowing.
太厲害了
Okay, wait.
等一下
Give me the details. Which part? What did he do?
把細節告訴我 哪部分？他做了什麼？
He was just
他就是
so good at it.
很厲害
So skilled.
技巧非常好
He paid close attention to my reactions.
他非常關注我的反應
Even though we aren't lovers or friends,
雖然我們不是情人，也不是朋友
it was like we were completely in sync.
但我們很合拍
It made me realize how important it is to have a good technique.
這讓我意識到技巧真的很重要
When you need something done, turn to a pro. Really.
原來要把事情做好 還是得去找專家，真的
Oh, wow.
是嗎？
But if it was that good, wouldn't you get addicted?
但如果真的有那麼好 妳不會上癮嗎？
No, I think I'll be okay
應該不會
since it costs money.
畢竟要花錢
Actually, it got me excited
其實，我倒是有點興奮
and now I want to have sex with Otoyan.
現在想和二也做愛了
You can escape the sexless phase.
終於要擺脫無性階段啦
We don't know yet.
現在還不知道呢
But now, instead of aggressively pushing for it like I did before,
但我想這次可以 用更溫和、更體貼的心態嘗試
I think I can try again with a more gentle and considerate approach this time.
不用像以前那樣把自己逼得太緊
Is it really a good thing that a young pro got you excited?
年輕的性愛高手讓妳動了春心 到底是不是好事呢？
He was incredibly good, right?
他床功一流，對吧？
So can sex with your husband satisfy you?
那妳老公還能滿足妳嗎？
Wouldn't you compare the two of them?
妳不會拿他們比較嗎？
Sorry. It's not like I know anything about Otoya's technique.
抱歉，我並不知道二也的技術如何
It's just a general observation.
只是一般而論
So…
那…
As a general observation,
一般而論
it's like the difference between enjoying a professional chef's cooking
就像吃專業主廚做的大餐
and something home-cooked.
和吃家常菜的區別一樣
They each give you a different kind of joy, nourishment, and comfort.
兩者都可以給你味覺享受 還有養分和寬慰
So they are different, but each one is good on its own. I think.
所以兩者不一樣 但各有各的優點，應該是這樣
Talking about sex like this makes it kind of bland.
以這種方式談性有點沒情趣
Well, anyway,
總之
I pray that you and your husband become the first couple
希望你們能成為第一對成功擺脫
to get out of the sexless phase.
無性狀態的夫妻
To score a score, huh?
枯木逢春？
No dad jokes, please.
別說大叔才會說的哏
Okay.
好
What?
怎麼了？
Mama!
媽媽
Hiro.
小宏
Thank you for today.
今天多謝了
Let's change your shoes.
來換鞋子吧
Mrs. Kashiwagi.
小宏媽媽
Hiro changed all of his clothes by himself for the first time today.
今天小宏第一次自己換了全身的衣服
-Really? -Yes.
-真的嗎？ -是的
That's great, Hiro.
好厲害，小宏
He's slowly learning to do more things.
他在慢慢學習，會做的事越來越多了
Right, Hiro.
對吧，小宏？
Hiro.
小宏
You're amazing. Doing your best every day.
你真了不起，每天都很努力
Mama will do her best too.
媽媽也會盡最大努力的
I'll do my best to be someone really cool.
我會努力成為一個很酷的人
So give me a hug.
來抱抱
Thank you, Hiro.
謝謝你，小宏
Mama.
媽媽
I love you.
我愛你
Hey, Otoyan.
二也
Can you set the table with our seats next to each other?
今天我們能並排坐嗎？
Why?
為什麼？
I just feel like eating next to you.
我想靠著你吃飯
Have some, have some.
請喝
Thank you, thank you.
謝謝
-Pour for me? -Sure.
-幫我倒一點？ -好
-Have some, have some. -Thank you, thank you.
-請喝 -謝謝
Okay.
好
-Now, cheers. -Cheers.
-乾杯
So good.
好喝
These cups you bought are really cute.
妳買的酒杯真可愛
Thank you.
謝謝
-Is it good? The turnip and salmon. -Yeah.
好吃嗎？蘿蔔和鮭魚
-Yummy.
好吃
Sitting like this is like that movie, The Family Game.
我們這麼坐就像《家族遊戲》裡那樣
-Yeah. It feels different. -Yeah.
對，感覺不同
What?
怎麼了？
I was thinking about how I like your face.
我在想我很喜歡你的臉
What? Really?
真的嗎？
-Yeah. -Which part?
哪個部分？
You have really good features,
你的五官很好看
but sometimes you are not that attractive.
但有時候又沒有那麼帥
What does that mean?
那是什麼意思？
No, for real.
我說真的
Ichiko.
小一
I think I'm all healed.
我已經痊癒了
Healed?
痊癒？
Yeah. My crotch.
下面那裡
Okay.
這樣啊
So,
那…
how about tonight?
今晚怎麼樣？
Okay.
好
Our relationship is going well.
我們相處得非常好
It might not be a happy marriage.
或許算不上模範夫妻
We had our hurdles
我們遇到過障礙
and got hurt.
受過傷
Well, only Otoyan got hurt.
應該說，只有二也受過傷
But even when our hearts and bodies were with other people,
但就算我們的身體和心靈 和別人在一起
neither of us ever thought about leaving this marriage.
我們都從沒想過要放棄這段婚姻
-Can I eat the meat? -Go ahead.
-我能吃這塊肉嗎？ -吃吧
The egg is so good.
這個蛋好好吃
We can make up as many times as we need.
無論多少次，我們都能和好如初
That's how we can make our marriage work for us.
我們就這樣經營著婚姻
Sorry, Ichiko.
對不起，小一
You don't need to be sorry.
你不必道歉
You've been through a lot.
這段時間你吃了不少苦
It happens.
這也是沒辦法的事
Thank you.
謝謝
Ichiko.
小一
Let me pleasure you.
我來取悅妳吧
Otoyan gave it his all,
二也盡了最大努力
and he did it with love.
他這麼做時，心懷愛意
He did it for me,
他是為了我這麼做
but…
可是…
it was like, "What?
我當時心想…就這樣嗎？
Was that it?"
這樣就沒了嗎？
No, no. I'm not comparing him to a pro.
不，我沒有拿他和專業的比較
And it's not Otoyan's fault.
而且這不是二也的錯
Right. Love. We love each other.
對，愛，我們彼此相愛
STAG ENERGY
（雄鹿雄風）
However…
然而…
No way.
不會吧
Why?
為什麼？
It won't.
起不來
Was sex something this serious and grave?
性愛什麼時候 成了這麼嚴肅、沉重的事？
Hey, Otoyan.
二也
Wouldn't it be good to take it easy instead of forcing yourself?
別太勉強自己，還是慢慢來吧？
You're right.
妳說得對
Even after we break up,
即使我們分手了
I don't want you to have sex with anyone else.
我也不希望你和別人上床
This is bad.
不妙了
If I don't forget about what she said,
如果我忘不了她的話
I will…
那我…
It's okay.
沒關係
We both want it
我們都想做
so we'll be able to do it eventually.
所以遲早會成功的
Then contact me if you need anything.
有什麼需要，儘管聯繫我
Even if it's just to talk.
哪怕只是聊聊天
When you need something done,
原來要把事情做好，還是得去找專家
turn to a pro, right?
對吧？
So, how are things now?
最近怎麼樣？
Is your husband still refusing you?
妳老公還拒絕妳嗎？
No. We got past that.
沒有，我們已經解決那個問題了
Now we're in the let's-rekindle-the-flame-and-do-it phase.
現在我們處於“上床重燃愛火”的階段
Oh, nice.
那很好啊
Well,
我覺得
I think we're doing good most of the time.
大部分的時候，我們相處得很好
But
可是
we have not--
我們沒有…
My husband's isn't at all…
我老公完全沒辦法…
Is that what's going on?
是這樣啊？
He's getting more and more depressed,
他越來越沮喪
and I'm trying to act as if it's okay,
我裝出不在乎的樣子
but it's not okay at all.
但我真的很擔心
Rei, have you ever been asked for advice about that at your job?
禮，你工作時 有人諮詢過這類問題嗎？
Yeah, sometimes.
有時候會
But it's difficult.
但這種問題很棘手
It's not like I can give answers like an expert.
我沒辦法像專家一樣答疑解惑
But it seems to happen the most with very serious guys.
但似乎越是嚴肅的男人 越容易遇到這種問題
Serious? I guess he is.
嚴肅？好像是
My husband is a very serious man.
我老公確實是個很嚴肅的男人
If it's a psychological problem,
如果是心理問題
there's always counseling.
可以求助心理醫生
Go to a hospital? I wonder if he would.
去醫院？他恐怕不肯
Even if he keeps trying, it will only make him feel more pressured.
如果他繼續勉強自己，只會壓力更大
That's true.
確實
Having said that,
另一方面
you'll end up drifting apart if you stop having a physical relationship.
如果沒有肌膚之親 你們夫妻只會越來越疏遠
So,
那…
instead of doing it for sex, are you both able to touch and hug each other?
如果不以性愛為目的 你們平時可以自然地
Naturally?
擁抱、接觸嗎？
Yes, but
可以，但是
I guess it's a bit unnatural.
可能有點不太自然
I see.
這樣啊
Okay, then…
好，那麼…
Okay, bye.
好，再見
Bye.
再見
Thanks.
謝謝
See you.
拜拜
Hello? This is Ichiko Aihara.
喂？我是相原一子
Yes.
是的
The competition from the other day?
前幾天的比賽嗎？
Really?
真的？
Yes.
好
Thank you. Yes.
謝謝，好
I can do it.
沒關係
Yes.
好
Thank you.
謝謝
Goodbye.
再見
Yes.
太好了
MOM
（媽媽）
Hello, Mom?
喂？媽媽
-Did you hear? The unofficial notice. -What?
你聽說了嗎？非正式通知
It was so blatant. Some of the younger ones will be sent to useless positions.
太誇張了，比較年輕的員工 會被調去超涼的工作
Really? Like who?
真的？誰啊？
Otoya Aihara.
相原二也
Isn't it good for him? There's no overtime in that department.
這對他來說不是好事嗎？ 那樣就不用加班了
He looks like he likes not having work.
他好像就喜歡清閒的工作
That's true.
那倒是
-Excuse me. -Sure.
-借過 -好
Hi.
你好
Did he hear us?
他聽到了嗎？
I don't know.
不知道
Shit.
糟糕
-You think he heard us? -He must have.
-妳覺得他聽到了嗎？ -一定聽到了
SALES PROMOTION AND PLANNING DEPT - FILE ROOM
（銷售策劃部，檔案室）
What's up, Ichiko?
出什麼事了，小一？
Sorry to call you at work.
抱歉在工作時間打給你
Can you talk?
方便說話嗎？
Yeah, I was about to go to lunch.
我正準備去吃午餐
Thanks.
謝謝
My mom called me.
我媽剛打電話來
It looks like they found a polyp or a hernia in her medical exams.
說在健檢時發現了息肉或者疝氣
Is she okay?
她沒事吧？
She said she's having minor surgery tomorrow
她說明天要動個小手術
and is suddenly feeling nervous about it.
突然覺得很緊張
She didn't say it,
雖然她沒有明講
but it looks like she wants me to be there.
但我感覺她希望我去陪她
But I have an important meeting tomorrow for a new project.
但我明天有很重要的會議 要談新案子的事
I'll go. Tomorrow is my day off anyway.
我去吧，反正我明天休假
Are you sure?
可以嗎？
I'm so sorry about this. That would be a big help.
真對不起，你可是幫了我好大的忙
It's okay.
不要緊
Then thank you.
那多謝啦
No problem.
不客氣
Mother.
媽媽
You did great.
您辛苦了
The polyp was safely removed.
息肉已經成功切除
How are you feeling?
您現在感覺如何？
That anesthetic.
打了麻藥
It made me so relaxed.
感覺特別放鬆
I fell right asleep counting to three.
剛數到三就睡著了
It would be nice to die like that.
如果能這麼死去，那該多好
If you're thirsty, here. Drink this.
口渴了吧？來，喝點這個
How kind of you.
真貼心
Thank you.
謝謝
That is very convenient.
這吸管真方便
The store was selling it too.
店裡也有賣
Ichiko would never be this thoughtful.
一子就不會這麼體貼
She probably would give me the bottle without the straw.
她可能會直接給我瓶子，沒有吸管
Then I'd spill it.
我若把水灑出來
And she'd get mad and throw me a tissue.
她就會發脾氣，扔給我一張紙巾
That's how she is.
她就是這種人
A girl like that
這樣的女孩子
makes me worry about her being a mother.
將來怎麼當得了母親
She's so inconsiderate and does everything her way.
她一點都不為他人著想 凡事我行我素
Don't mothers have to put their child's happiness first?
當母親的不就該 把孩子的幸福放在第一位嗎？
That's right.
是啊
But I suppose
但我看
it will be hard for her to have children.
她大概很難生小孩了
She's already quite old.
都這把年紀了
And giving birth when you're older is…
上了年紀生孩子可是…
Otoya.
二也
You like children, right?
你很喜歡孩子吧？
So…
所以…
I feel so bad and sorry for you.
我真為你感到可惜
No, it's fine.
沒有的事
I'm okay.
我沒關係
NEW WAYS OF CONNECTING PEOPLE AND THE SEA
（連接人與海洋的新方式）
I'm home.
我回來了
You surprised me.
嚇我一跳
-I'm home. -Welcome back.
-我回來了 -你回來啦
So you were working here.
妳在這裡工作啊？
Yeah. The tea table is here.
是啊，茶几在這裡
And I can concentrate when I hide away like this.
像這樣窩著可以更專注
Right. Thank you for looking after my mom.
對了，謝謝你照顧我媽
You really helped me out.
你真的幫了我好大的忙
Sure. It's good that it wasn't anything serious.
不會，還好沒有大礙
She always makes a big deal of things.
她總喜歡小題大做
I'll buy you anything you want for dinner. I'm getting a lot of money from this job.
晚餐想吃什麼儘管說，我請客 這個案子能賺好多錢
Okay…
好…
Sorry, I'll take this work call.
抱歉，我得接一下，是工作的事
Okay. Good night.
好，晚安
Good night.
晚安
Hello, this is Ichiko Aihara.
喂？我是相原一子
Sure.
對
Oh, yes.
是的
Welcome.
歡迎光臨
-For one? -Yes, I'm alone.
-一位嗎？ -對，我一個人來的
I'll have a gimlet.
我要一杯琴蕾
Sure.
好
-Thanks. -No problem.
-謝謝 -不客氣
You already drank quite a bit, huh?
您已經喝了不少吧？
Oh, shut up.
閉嘴啦
-Here you are. -Thanks.
-您的酒 -謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝
It was nothing.
沒事
I'm gonna turn it off.
我要把它關掉
Sorry.
不好意思
You picked it up for me, but…
還麻煩你幫我撿起來
It's all right.
沒關係
I had a big fight with my fiancé.
我和未婚夫大吵了一架
So I don't want to talk to him right now.
所以現在不想理他
I see.
這樣啊
You're married, right?
你結婚了吧？
Yes.
是的
Sorry about being drunk.
我喝醉了，對不起
But aren't there times like this even when you're married?
但哪怕結了婚 也會遇到這種情況吧？
When you don't want to see your wife's face.
不想看到你妻子的臉
Yes, sometimes.
有時候會
I knew it.
果然
Hold on.
等等
Don't tell me.
難道說
Today? You too?
今天你跟我一樣？
I see.
原來如此
Your hands…
你的手…
are so big and beautiful.
又大又好看
Wanna leave
想不想
and go somewhere else with me?
跟我去別的地方？
Somewhere else?
別的地方？
Somewhere else.
別的地方
I can, but
可以是可以
I'll be thinking about my wife the entire time.
但是我會一直想著我的妻子
If that's okay with you, then sure.
如果妳不介意，那去也無妨
What's with this guy?
這人是怎麼回事？
He's so mean.
好惡劣
I'm done. The bill please.
我喝完了，請幫我買單
Sure. Thank you.
好的，謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝
BOOKS SUMIYOSHI BOOKS - STATIONARY
（住吉書店，書，文具）
LOST YANYAN PICTURE BOOK AVAILABLE!
（《迷路的巖巖》，繪本熱銷中！）
BY TAKASHI HINOI
（《迷路的巖巖》 作者：明日高司）
We have to change,
我們必須做出改變
both you and I.
你我都要改變
CHILDCARE / DEVELOPMENTAL DISABILITIES
（育兒，發育障礙）
TEACHING NON-COGNITIVE SKILLS
（教授非認知技能，過動症）
AND HOME CARE
（發育障礙和家庭護理）
INTERPERSONAL RELATIONSHIP ISSUES
（人際關係問題）
ADHD - CARELESSNESS IS A TRAIT
（過動症-容易粗心大意）
A BOOK TO HELP YOU UNDERSTAND DEVELOPMENTAL DISABILITIES
（一本幫助您瞭解發育障礙的書）
TECHNIQUES TO CALM TANTRUMS OF CHILDREN
（如何安撫有發育障礙的兒童）
I'm back.
我回來了
-How pretty. -It is.
-真漂亮 -是啊
It's so pretty, right?
好美，對吧？
That's right.
對啊
One of the flowers we'll be using today is the Chinese peony.
今天用到的花，其中一種是牡丹
Everyone, be sure to arrange it in your own style.
大家一定要插出一盆 屬於自己風格的花
-Yes.
-好 -好的
In the flower language,
對了
the red Chinese peony means "honest" and "faithful."
紅牡丹的花語是“誠實”、“忠實”
A white Chinese peony means a "happy marriage."
白牡丹則寓意“婚姻美滿”
-Oh, wow. -That's nice.
好棒
Now let's have some fun.
我們來享受樂趣吧
-Yes. -Okay.
-好 -好的
-Isn't it an impressive flower? -Amazing.
-這花真漂亮 -太美了
The gerbera daisy is also very large.
非洲菊也很大
This one is also a new variety.
這也是一個新品種
-I'm back. -Welcome back.
-我回來了 -你回來啦
What is that, Otoyan?
二也，那是什麼？
What? Oh, this?
這個嗎？
This is a Chinese peony.
這是牡丹
A white peony means--
白牡丹代表著…
Not that.
我不是說這個
Don't tell me you're still going to that flower class.
難不成你還在上花道課？
Why didn't you quit?
為什麼還去？
Listen, Ichiko.
是這樣的，小一
Mitsuki already left the class. She's moving with her family.
美月已經不去上課了 她和家人要搬去外地
It's not about whether she's there or not.
這和她在不在無關
Why are you still going to the class where you both met, like you still miss her?
你為什麼還去你們相遇的地方？ 彷彿你還在想她一樣
What exactly do you want to do?
你到底想幹什麼？
Ikebana.
學花道啊
Besides, it would look weird if I quit right after she left.
而且如果她一走我就走了，會很奇怪
In the first place, I started going because I wanted to learn ikebana.
我剛開始就是因為想學花道 才會去那裡
I have no reason to quit.
我沒理由退出
Don't put that in our home.
別把那種東西放在家裡
I'm going back to work.
我去工作了
-Ichiko. -What?
-小一 -幹什麼？
I didn't get a chance to say this the other day,
我前幾天沒有機會跟妳說
but you should be nicer to your mom.
但妳應該對妳媽媽好一點
At least give her a call.
至少打個電話給她
Sure, she likes to exaggerate,
她確實喜歡小題大作
but she is sick and scared.
但她生病了，心裡很害怕
Okay.
知道了
You bastard.
混蛋
You dumb bastard.
可惡
MOM
（媽媽）
A message should be okay.
傳封簡訊就可以了吧
PLEASE ANSWER THE PHONE. I CALLED OTOYA.
（麻煩妳接電話，我打給二也了）
OKAY. WE WILL ARRIVE SOON
（好，我們馬上就到）
REI - HELLO, ICHIKO.
（禮：一子，妳好）
IT'S REI FROM SALON FLOWER GARDEN
（我是花園館的禮）
Rei.
禮
WERE THERE ANY CHANGES TO YOUR SEXLESS PROBLEM?
（妳的無性問題有進展嗎？）
I FOUND SOME NEW INFORMATION TO TELL YOU NEXT TIME WE MEET
（我有一些新訊息 下次見面時告訴妳）
He could have sent it in the message. But he wrote "next time we meet."
他本來可以直接在簡訊裡說 但他卻說“下次見面時”
Oh, Rei.
禮呀
-Good morning.
-早安
That smells nice.
好香
Here.
給妳
Thanks.
謝謝
Hey, Ichiko.
小一
I think I'll quit the ikebana class.
我不會再去上花道課了
I realized I was being insensitive,
之前是我不好
not thinking about your feelings.
沒有顧及妳的感受
What? Why?
為什麼？
I thought about it too.
我也想過了
I got emotional and blew up at you without listening to what you had to say.
我沒聽你解釋就亂發脾氣
And so I think I wasn't thinking clearly.
之前是我沒想清楚
Sorry.
對不起
Otoyan, you should keep going.
二也，你繼續去上課吧
Since you like it so much, it will be a shame if you quit.
難得你那麼喜歡，不去上好可惜
Don't we need relief and joy in our lives?
生活中需要慰藉和歡喜，不是嗎？
And that is okay?
真的可以嗎？
It's perfectly okay.
當然可以
Thank you for your waiting. Here is your tea.
久等了，您的茶來了
Thank you.
謝謝
I thought this was a good idea when I heard about it.
我聽了以後覺得這個主意不錯
Let's call her Miss B. Her marriage had been sexless for over a year.
比方說，有位B小姐 她的無性婚姻已經持續了一年多
She hasn't gone to a concert in a while, but when she went,
她好久沒去聽音樂會 然後有一天她去了
she was turned on by the sexy, mature singer.
性感的熟齡歌手讓她春心大動
She got home still feeling hot and bothered,
她回到家，仍然慾火焚身
immediately pounced on her sleeping husband and scored.
於是她立刻向熟睡的丈夫求歡 結果乾柴烈火
Scored a score.
枯木逢春
Now she says
現在她說
every time they have a dry spell, she goes to that artist's concert
每次缺乏動力時 她就去看那位藝人演唱
to get herself in the mood.
來讓自己進入狀態
I see.
原來如此
Is that artist Okamura-chan?
那位藝人是岡村嗎？
No, I didn't ask.
不，我沒問那麼多
Oh, and there are couples who are dry like a rock garden
還有那種“枯山水”型的夫妻
where both agree it's okay if that is not a part of their relationship.
雙方達成了共識 婚姻中沒有性也沒關係
But don't the women in those couples go to you for treatment?
但那種類型夫妻裡的女方 會找你做治療吧？
Yeah, they do.
是的
So I guess there are some people who believe they don't need their partners
也就是說，有些人相信 因為有你這樣的人存在
to satisfy their desires or give them sexual fulfillment
所以他們不需要伴侶 來滿足他們的慾望
because people like you exist.
或是給予他們性滿足
Should I say thank you?
我該說謝謝嗎？
Me making another appointment with you is an entirely different matter.
我又約你出來完全是兩碼事
Of course.
那是當然
Actually, Ichiko.
一子
I'm going to quit the salon at the end of this month.
這個月底我就要辭職了
Oh, really?
是嗎？
I was only doing it until I saved enough money for graduate school.
之前做這行是為了賺研究所的學費
I wanted to tell you in person.
我想當面告訴妳
You did tell me when we first met.
你從一開始就這麼跟我說過
You've really got it together.
真是青年有為
Good luck with your studies.
祝你學業順利
Ichiko. Don't make that face.
一子，別露出那種表情
Can I sit next to you?
我能坐在妳旁邊嗎？
Look at me.
看著我
Welcome.
歡迎光臨
Ordering take out?
外帶嗎？
-Yes. -Okay.
-對 -好的
One Ethiopian and one Guatemalan, please.
一包衣索比亞，一包瓜地馬拉，謝謝
Okay.
好的
Are these the right ones?
是這些嗎？
Yes.
是的
That will be 3,500 yen.
一共是3500日元
-That is the exact change. -Yes.
剛好不用找零
-Thank you.
-謝謝
-Our apologies. -I'm sorry.
-非常抱歉 -對不起
That surprised me. Is it okay?
嚇我一跳，沒事吧？
Yeah, everything is okay.
沒事
Thank you.
謝謝光臨
Ichiko?
一子？
Was that your husband? The person looking this way?
那個人是妳老公嗎？往這邊看的那個
Oh, okay.
這樣啊
Did I do something bad?
我做錯什麼了嗎？
Since I'm sitting close to you.
坐得離妳這麼近
We were holding hands too.
我們還握著手
Friends do that too, don't they?
朋友之間也會這樣吧？
Friends don't normally hold hands, right?
朋友一般不會握著彼此的手吧？
Really?
是嗎？
But
但是
I think it will be okay.
我覺得應該沒關係
My husband doesn't care about this stuff.
我老公不在意這種事
He's not the jealous type.
他不是那種會吃醋的人
Plus we have an open relationship.
再說，我們是開放式的婚姻
Okay.
好吧
Otoyan?
二也
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
Sorry for going through your phone.
抱歉看了妳的手機
Don't do it anymore.
以後別這樣了
I was curious since
我只是很好奇
you were acting lovey-dovey at the café, not caring about what other people think.
你們在咖啡店裡表現得那麼恩愛 完全不在乎周圍人的眼光
That was a friend.
我們只是普通朋友
Friend?
朋友？
Is that why you were flirting at a place I also shop at?
所以你們才會 在我經常去的店裡調情？
"Hello, Ichiko.
“一子，妳好
It's Rei from Salon Flower Garden.
我是花園館的禮
Were there any changes to your sexless problem?"
妳的無性問題有進展嗎？”
You were talking about me
妳在跟那個朋友
with that friend.
談我的事
Those messages came
這些簡訊
from that man you were with today, right?
就是今天那個男人傳給妳的吧？
-That's right. -Who is he?
-是的 -他是什麼人？
Tell me, what exactly are you doing?
告訴我，妳到底在幹什麼？
He is…
他是…
a fortune-teller.
算命師
He's famous for reading tarot cards despite how he looks.
你別看他那樣 其實他是個塔羅牌占卜高手
He's young but really skilled and has proven results. So my friend introduced--
他雖然年輕，但算命很準 所以我朋友介紹…
So you'd say, "I'm really happy I slept with you, Rei. Thank you,"
“禮，能和你做愛 我真的很開心，謝謝你”
to a tarot-reading psychic.
妳對算命師說這種話
Why…
為什麼…
Why?
為什麼？
Ichiko.
小一
I don't need obvious lies like that.
我不需要這種拙劣的謊言
What is the Flower Garden?
這個“花園館”是什麼地方？
Where did you meet him?
妳在哪裡認識他的？
-At the salon. -What kind of salon?
-在花園館 -那是什麼地方？
Beauty salon.
美容院
There are men in that beauty salon?
美容院裡有男人？
It's considered a beauty salon.
表面上是美容院
To put it simply…
其實就是…
it's a brothel.
風俗館
A brothel?
風俗館？
Ichiko.
小一
You bought a man with money. I see.
妳花錢買春，原來如此
It's payment for services received.
這只是一項付費服務而已
Just so you know, I only slept with him once.
順便一提，我只跟他做了一次
Your affair lasted over a year. You had sex with Mitsuki multiple times--
你的婚外情持續了一年多 你和美月做了不知道多少次…
Now wait a minute, Ichiko.
等一下，小一
The number isn't the problem, okay?
這不是次數的問題，好嗎？
My affair was something we discussed and decided together.
我的婚外情是我們雙方討論決定的
And you were happy with that since you didn't want to have sex.
因為妳不想做愛，所以妳不介意
And I never hid it from you.
而且我也從來沒有瞞著妳
I fell in love and slept with someone I like.
我愛上了一個我喜歡的人 並且和她發生關係
What about you?
可是妳呢？
You bought a younger man with money.
妳用錢買了個年輕的男公關
It's completely different.
那完全不一樣
That's prostitution.
那是嫖妓
Do you like him, Ichiko?
小一，妳喜歡他嗎？
It's not about that.
不是那樣的
So you're okay with having sex with a man you don't even like.
妳都不喜歡他，就能和他發生關係
I needed to.
我必須那麼做
I wasn't okay with it.
我並不覺得光彩
Not one bit.
一點也不
I was so scared and kept hesitating.
我當時很害怕，也一直很猶豫
But it was something I really needed.
但我真的很有必要那麼做
I used up my time, courage, and money to go there.
我花了好長時間、好多錢 鼓足勇氣才去了那裡
I took on all the risks and responsibilities. I was serious.
我承擔了所有風險和責任 我是認真的
But that's what saved me.
但那麼做救了我
And this is my problem.
而且這是我自己的問題
You don't have any right to get mad at me for it.
你無權指責我
Do…
妳…
Do you really…
妳真的…
think so?
這麼想？
Hey, wait.
等一下
Hey, Otoyan. Where are you going?
二也，你要去哪兒？
Don't touch me.
別碰我
That wasn't jealousy.
這不是吃醋
That was definitely
那個絕對是
a look of disdain.
鄙視的眼神
The strength he used to push me away
他甩開我的力道
made me realize
讓我意識到
Otoyan is a man.
二也是個男人
TEST RESULTS PREGNANT - NOT PREGNANT
（驗孕結果：已懷孕）
NEXT EPISODE
（下集預告）
We need some time apart to calmly think about things.
我們需要分開一段時間 冷靜一下，把事情想清楚
THEY HAVE SEPARATED!
（他們分居了！）
Is it really bad? Mud-fight bad?
真的很嚴重嗎？撕破臉了？
It's nice that you could talk to her like a friend.
你能像對朋友一樣跟她交心是很好
But I guess she really became your friend.
但她恐怕真變成你的朋友了吧
Are you lonely now with Otoya gone?
二也走了，妳會很孤單嗎？
Yeah.
會
Just living together with a partner you get along with is priceless.
一起生活的夫妻能和睦相處
I want to have the baby.
我想把孩子生下來
Do you know who the father is?
妳知不知道孩子是誰的？
It made me want to see you.
於是突然很想見到一子
A NEW LOVE?
（一段新戀情？）
We might have been stuck circling the same spot in the past
以前我們在同一個地方
We were serious, weren't we?
我們是認真的，不是嗎？
We never broke up.
我們從沒放棄這段婚姻
THE HAPPINESS THEY CHOSE IS…
（他們選擇的幸福是…）
THIS IS A WORK OF FICTION.
（本劇純屬虛構）
Subtitle: Annie Chen
字幕翻譯：紀小敏